novoed.com 2018-08-28

# NovoEd Cookie Policy - NovoEd

_Effective starting date: 25th May 2018_

This Cookie Policy (‘Policy’, henceforth) describes NovoEd’s (affiliates ‘we’, ‘us’, ‘our’, or ‘NovoEd’) cookie handling practices, and how we makes use of cookies to collect information that helps us improve your online experience.

These information are collected when you visit our website ([https://www.NovoEd.com](http://www.novoed.com/)), any of our documents linked to this Policy, use our application, or even if you are visiting any of our client who are using our platform to power their site. The collected information may include personal information or other information considered personal, such as your browser details, the date and time of your visit, and even your Internet Protocol address.

The Policy covers in detail the technologies used by us, why we use them, and your rights to opt in or out of being tracked in your NovoEd account with cookies.

  * What are cookies? 
  * Types of cookies 
  * What cookies do we use? 
  * How and why do we use cookies? 
  * How to control and disable cookies? 
  * Opt-out of cookies through browser 
  * Consent 
  * Updates to this notice 

Cookies are small text files that are downloaded by the browser that you use to reach and use our service. These cookies collect, store, and share data of your activities across websites. They are mainly used to learn about your actions when you interact with the sites and services and “remember” you and your preferences, such as your preferred browser or language, either for a single visit (via a ‘session cookie’) or for multiple visits (using a ‘persistent cookie’).

We use both session-based and persistent cookies. Here’s what they are:

  * Session cookies are temporary and last only while your browser is open. They are deleted from your device when you leave the service.
  * Persistent cookies remain in your browser or device for a much longer time mostly until your browser deletes them or when they reach their expiry date, depending on the cookie. They are unique and allow us to perform site analytics and customization, among other similar things.

Cookies may be set by either the site that you are visiting (‘first party cookies’) or by third parties, such as those who use our services (‘third party cookies’). More information on cookies can be found at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

The table below explains the types of cookies we use on our websites and why we use them.

**Category  ** | **Why we use these cookies?**  
---|---  
**Necessary** | These cookies are strictly necessary to perform important activities such as allowing registered users to authenticate themselves to secure areas and perform account related functions.  
**Preference**    | These cookies allow our services to recognize you and remember your preferences when using our services. This enables us to personalize our content for you and provide you with a more personal experience without you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit our Services.  
**Security** | These cookies help to detect, identify, and prevent suspicious or malicious activities on our services. They also detect authentication failures and take measures to increase the security of the service  
**Analytics** | These cookies collect information on how users interact with our services. This helps us understand how well our services are doing and what improvements are need. This enables us to operate our Services more efficiently, and to research and develop new Services and features.  
**Third-Party**

**OR**

**Embedded Content**

| Cookies operated by third-party applications or service providers gather browsing activity across multiple websites and across multiple sessions and use them to enhance the experience of website visitors. These cookies may be used for providing certain statistical and analytics purposes and can help to prevent fraudulent traffic or other suspicious activities. They are usually a persistent cookie and continue to stay in your system until you delete them or they expire based on the time period set in each third-party cookie.  
Please note that we have no direct control over the information collected by these cookies or how they use them. So it is advisable to review each third-party’s cookie disclosure before consenting to this use category.  
  
While there are several types of cookies (as specified in the ‘types of cookies’ section), NovoEd uses ‘Strictly Necessary’, ‘Preference’, and ‘Third-Party’ cookies. 

‘Strictly Necessary’ cookies are required for using our sites and services. If you refuse to accept these cookies, we are not liable for any security breach nor can we predict how our sites and services will perform. Some of the Strictly Necessary cookies that we use are Intercom and Authentication.

We use ‘Preference’ cookies to track your behaviour and remember your preferences.

The ‘Third-Party’ cookies that we use include Google Analytics, ZenDesk and NewRelic.  You can turn them off by disabling cookies on your browser, for more information go to the [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/), [NewRelic Privacy Policy](https://newrelic.com/termsandconditions/privacy), and [Zendesk Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/).

NovoEd uses cookies to identify you as a unique user, remember you preferences, tailor our products to suit your interests and needs, and to track your usage of our sites and services. Likewise, we may also use cookies to restrict you from accessing certain content or features, protect our sites and services, and to carry out the requests that you make. 

NovoEd uses third-party applications to provide better service to all our users. These apps and services make use of persistent cookies to improve user experience, analyze user behavior, and manage content.  

You have the right to decide whether or not to accept cookies and similar technologies. If, however, you choose to disable cookies, it may affect the availability and functionality of some components or features of NovoEd.

Most browsers accept cookies, by default. However, they provide ways that allow you to change cookie settings in order to make the browser refuse certain types of cookies or at least inform you before accepting cookies. You can make these changes either through the browser’s inbuilt settings or through external plugins. The procedure for changing cookie settings is different for different browsers. You can go to the help page of your browser to learn more. 

If you do not opt out of accepting cookies, you agree to the collection, usage as well as sharing of your details, including your personal data, by us and by the various third-party apps (subject to their privacy and cookie policies) that we use. You can change cookie setting to revoke your consent anytime by following the steps mentioned in the ‘How to control and disable cookie settings’ section given above. 

This policy may be updated from time to time.  If there are any changes to this policy, we will notify you by changing the ‘effective starting’ date located at the top of this policy.
